<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:iweb="http://www.apple.com/iweb" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>VGMoose’s Hacking Tutorials</title>
    <link>http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Tutorials/Tutorials.html</link>
    <description>Here’s where various ROM hacking tutorials lurk. Most of the tutorials will reference the tools provided in the “Downloads” section up above, but will apply anywhere as long as you have the required tools downloaded.</description>
    <generator>iWeb 3.0.2</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Tutorials/Tutorials_files/tututs.jpg</url>
      <title>VGMoose’s Hacking Tutorials</title>
      <link>http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Tutorials/Tutorials.html</link>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Fourth and Fifth Gen Etiquette</title>
      <link>http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Tutorials/Entries/2011/2/24_Fouth_Gen_Basics.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">46fb5c93-115f-485a-b62f-7b191053781b</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 11:25:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Tutorials/Entries/2011/2/24_Fouth_Gen_Basics_files/Screen%20shot%202011-02-24%20at%2011.32.42%20AM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Tutorials/Media/object075_1.png&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:217px; height:127px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;An introduction to everything new in the fourth gen and how things have changed since third gen hacking! NARC files confuse you? READ THIS. NARC files don’t actually confuse you that much? Whatever.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Alright well, before we get started, I’m just going to tell you straight up to go download my hacking tool pack for fourth generation. It’s under “Downloads” which can obviously be clicked on above&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Got everything downloaded? Okay. Now, do you have a NDS ROM? I’d recommend you rip yourself a HG/SS one for the sake of this tutorial, but if you’re unable to, you should still be able to pick up the general idea by reading, but you will not be able to follow along, at least, not as long as the .narc files go. Which come on, that’s totally why you’re reading this, isn’t it?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;So, let’s pop open that download pack that you definitely just downloaded. More specifically, let’s pop open KiwiEditor (it’s right in the root of the folder):&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Got it? Good. Kiwi will allow us to unpack the ROM, but we’re just browsing today. Okay, so, go to File -&gt; Open and select your (HGSS) nds ROM.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Yay! This is much like Windows Explorer, or Finder now. You’re viewing the files that you have loaded into Kiwi. Now, double click on your .nds file (in my case, soulsilvery.nds)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This window will appear! Like I said before, just like windows explorer, this is a file browser. Click on the plus sign next to the ROM name and you will view its contents, much like that of a folder.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;So, this is it. Each .NDS file is kind of like a .zip file, or .rar, or any kind of archive. There are files within it that allow it to function. Kiwi, among some other programs, allow us to view these internal components. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;But why do you care?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Well, this is where fourth and fifth gen hacking differ from third generation hacking. In third gen, you would simply load the entire .GBA file in whichever editor you needed and you would just save that file like any other. As .NDS files are so large, however, the process determined for them is to unpack, or unarchive, much like unzip, the files within the .NDS file. These little bits each have a role– some files within the .NDS file will contain all of the in  game text for example, while others will contain the script, or the pokémon sprites, or something of the like. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Feel free to do some poking around. In HGSS, all of the NARC files aren’t actually called NARC files. They’ve all been reorganized and place into this directory called “a” in the data directory, but they function just like the NARC files in Diamond or Pearl.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Woah wait, what’s a NARC file? Narc stands for Nintendo Archive, which makes it a lot less confusing. again, much like a zip file, these too contain smaller components. Nintendo put an archive in yo archive so you can archive while you archive.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Navigate to /data/a/0/8/1 and tick the check box, assuming you’re using a HGSS ROM. If not, look up the equivalent in the readme.txt file I’ve included for Diamond, Pearl, or Platinum. (it’s in msgdata/msgdata.narc incase you’re too lazy...)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Now click the farthest left icon that kind of looks like a piece of paper. This will extract the contents of a/0/8/1.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Wat. Where dey go? If you’ll kindly open up folder where your nds rom/roms reside...&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;You’ll notice there’s a new folder with the same name as your ROM! Click through this folder, and you’ll find a similar file system layout to the one you just navigated:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Now, unless you’ve checked already or are familiar with it, you may not know that the NARC that we just extracted contains the events. This includes the overworld sprites, which can be edited with BTX editor. But... wait. BTX editor.... edits .BTX files, doesn’t it? I’m not going to go into detail on BTX editor, but you do need to get the BTX files out of this narc in order to edit them. How do we do this?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Why, open the file in Kiwi editor! Kiwi also opens and extract NARC archives! Go to the main Kiwi screen and select open just as you did before, but this time, be sure to adjust the file type at the bottom:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Select all files (normally the NARC file would be recognized, but as HGSS uses a different NARC naming system, you must do this to tell the program that your NARC file isn’t a .narc. So anyway, open the 1 file in romname/data/a/0/8/:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;And it will be added just like your .nds file.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;And as you would expect... Clicking it reveals...&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;All of those yummy .BTX and etc files! You can then check the box next to the ones you want to extract to edit, (or check all at the top to get a nice index going) and they will be extracted to the same folder as the narc initially was. And those BTX files can be opened with BTX editor! (Try this out yourself– the BTX file with the number 70 is the female hero, for example).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Alright, so this is all very nice... but after you’ve gone through all of this... How do you go back to your simple .nds file? Well, there are two things that we have extracted. The NARC file was unpacked, and so was the NDS file. So you need to repack your NARC file with the modified inards (ie. the modified BTX file) and then from there, repack all of it back into a .nds, which you can then play in your emulator.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I wouldn’t be too concerned about decompiling and recompiling your ROM– when you work in PPRE (which you mostly likely will be doing... all of the time...) The “set rom” feature creates a full scale extraction of the .nds file in the folder “tmp_romname.” LIkewise, it can also be compiled at the end with “write rom.” You can use kiwi on the extracted files from ndstool or PPRE and then do the final compiling with PPRE or ndstool.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;So, to remake the NARC file. (I would suggest opening a BTX and editing it in BTX editor at this time– most likely the hero sprites located at 1_69 and 1_70 .BTX respectively. If you don’t want to make your own or modify the current ones, you can use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rickyayoub.com/ups/emeraldhero.PNG&quot;&gt;my own template from third gen&lt;/a&gt; as a test.) Head to the main screen of kiwi and select Tools -&gt; Make NARC file&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;It will then prompt you for what the input files will be, and where the output location is. You should fill both of these values in with the romname/data/a/0/8/ folder, like so:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;And, of course, click OK. I always include the FNTB, so check that box. Now this is actually a little confusing. Kiwi didn’t ask for a file name. It will always save the newly made narc as the last folder in the output .narc (so in this case, 8.narc), and it will be in the location you told it, or the same one with all of the 1 contents and .BTX files. So, at the very bottom of my data/a/0/8/1 folder is this:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Now, 8.narc is simply your edited “1” file. the “1” file is also in this directory, however, so you must delete the “1” file and then rename 8.narc to “1”.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;You don’t really have to worry about saving the original “1” file, instead I would suggest you back up the original .nds and just re-extract it if something goes horribly wrong during editing/compiling of a narc.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Once you have renamed the 8.narc file to 1 (in hgss), go back to the tools menu in kiwi and select make nds file.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Then fill out the fields appropriately:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;As you may have noticed, in my example, I have selected the same output folder that the ROM is in. Because of this, my old ROM will be overwritten. You can avoid this by backing up the original nds file, renaming the rom folder, or selecting an output folder different than the one the original rom resides in. (The name of your new rom will be the same name as the last source directory– which in this case is the same as our rom causing it to be overwritten).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Click OK and that’s it! Run your new ROM and you should see the changes made!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Do note that most of the time you will probably use PPRE or NDSTOOL to repackage the NDS file (both of which don’t always default to overwriting the old rom as kiwi does).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Happy hacking!&lt;br/&gt;VGMoose&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Tutorials/Entries/2011/2/24_Fouth_Gen_Basics_files/Screen%20shot%202011-02-24%20at%2011.32.42%20AM.png" length="22770" type="image/png"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Custom Text Tutorial</title>
      <link>http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Tutorials/Entries/2010/10/11_Custom_Text_Tutorial.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">537f106a-ae34-4c79-b722-7b7b955a2584</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2010 16:23:37 -0400</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Tutorials/Entries/2010/10/11_Custom_Text_Tutorial_files/Screen%20shot%202010-10-12%20at%201.02.49%20PM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Tutorials/Media/object117_1.png&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:217px; height:126px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;VIDEO TUTORIAL. This is it! The text editing tutorial! It’s really a lot easier than it looks! And kind of... fun. Scary right?&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The wonderful and amazing program you see above is none other than Advance-Text! It is simply the single best and greatest program (in my humble) opinion out there for beginner text editors. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;So, let’s get started. Bust out your A-Text copy which I have so mindfully included in my download pack. If you receive the following notification:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;It’s time to do some googling. Or look &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ascentive.com/support/new/support_dll.phtml?dllname=COMDLG32.OCX&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Download and follow the instructions on that page to install and register comdlg32.ocx.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Once all of that is out of the way, and you have A-Text up and running, simply open your ROM as you would with any of the other tools.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The ROM that you loaded may or may not activate one of the packaged INI files that tell it what the text pointers are. For this tutorial, however, we will not be using them. Fire up VBA and load up the ROM of the same name.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Take it away, me:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;	-	While playing the game find the text that you wish to edit.&lt;br/&gt;	-	Click on Search in Advance Text&lt;br/&gt;	-	Type the text exactly as it is in the game&lt;br/&gt;	-	Check the box that says “Start from Beginning”&lt;br/&gt;	-	Click Search button&lt;br/&gt;	-	If the text on the right is what you wish to edit, hit save and give it a name and category&lt;br/&gt;	-	Edit the text accordingly with the interface</description>
      <enclosure url="http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Tutorials/Entries/2010/10/11_Custom_Text_Tutorial_files/Screen%20shot%202010-10-12%20at%201.02.49%20PM.png" length="165095" type="image/png"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inserting Custom Pokémon Sprites</title>
      <link>http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Tutorials/Entries/2010/9/16_Making_Custom_Pokemon.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">d50824d7-6027-49bd-aa3a-8534641831e3</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2010 18:10:52 -0400</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Tutorials/Entries/2010/9/16_Making_Custom_Pokemon_files/Screen%20shot%202010-09-16%20at%206.12.34%20PM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Tutorials/Media/object118_1.png&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:216px; height:126px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Okay dude, it’s time to make your own Pokémon!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The process really isn’t as complicated as people make it out to be. The key here is doing it neatly. This guide will cover the process for Emerald version, but a similar (easier) method is available in all of the other third generation games. That will be discussed as well.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Okay, so, the first thing you’re going to want to do is find an appropriate Pokémon Sprite to edit. It doesn’t really matter what the image is, just keep in mind that it will drop in both color and resolution drastically when inserted into the game.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Open up unLZ-GBA in Hacking Tools &gt; Elitemap &gt; unLZ-GBA.exe&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;And... you’re done! NAH I KID!! It’s time to do some things. Serious things. Click on OpenFile and select the ROM that you wish to work with.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The above message may be displayed. Just click OK man. Jeez, no need to freak out.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Now, this certainly doesn’t look any less confusing! Okay, so here’s what’s happening: you’re viewing all of the sprites in the ROM. Some of them (like the one above,) are compressed and uneditable. Others, however, are free for you to manipulate to your will.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The way the images are stored are through the top number in the two number boxes. In order to change sprites, we will be entering a number into the top box, clicking goto, and then changing the sprite. The Next and Previous buttons can also be used to change images, but we’ll be using digits.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I’ve just entered a random digit, 1000, as an example. Watch what happens when I press Goto. NOTE: DO NOT CLICK ENTER. The program will crash. It’s tragic, I know.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;It looks like we’ve stumbled upon an attack animation. Now, in theory, you could swap this out for a bitmap, but that’s not what we’re here for. Continue searching for a Pokémon sprite image, or scroll down to the bottom of the page where the ranges are listed.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;GADFRIGGINZOOKS, I’ve stumbled upon a Pokémon image! Let’s just work from here for convenience. Click on the button on the right side that says “Save as...” and save it somewhere. Then, open MSPaint. This can be accomplished by going to Start &gt; Run and typing “mspaint.exe”, or by locating it under Accessories.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Microsoft Paint is the built in image editor for windows and it’s great because it’s so simple! Copy and paste the image you want to exchange it with over this one. By doing this, we will preserve both the dimensions and the palette of the original bitmap.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;My paste went smoothly! You might have to do some paint trimming to get it to fit. Just be sure to not change the dimensions. If the colors are wrong, you can adjust them manually, but I would recommended going back to unLZ-gba and choosing a different Pokémon’s to “Save as...” and edit in paint. Due to the limitations of the game boy, your sprites are limited to the installed palettes.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Here’s the repositioned edited sprite. Note how I used the same background fill as I did for Porygon 2. This is important, otherwise your Pokémon will either have a solid background behind it or have pieces of it transparent. Now that we’re done with this, save it, switch to unLZ-gba, and click “Import,” right underneath “Save as...” select the sprite you just saved.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Yay! Now, click “Write to Rom” You will be presented with another window. Click OK.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Onoes! When this message appears, try a different Pokémon. When you try a different Pokémon, make sure to change the settings to the ones below:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Keep trying until you get to a Pokémon that will let you write to it under these settings! After a successful write, you may think you’re done, but most likely you are not. Click Next and then Previous to reload your Pokémon’s sprite and you will see that the coloring is off.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;As you can see, this little feller has taken on Elekid’s palette. To fix this, we must Import again, only this time checking off the box titled “Export Palette.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The program might report an error, but that’s okay. We were only trying to export the palette, which will export regardless of whether or not there’s an error. Click Next and then Previous to see if your Pokémon’s sprite is completely satisfactory.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The reason why we can’t just export Palette from the start is for the same reason that the exporting palette works even after it claims to have failed– it would export the palette regardless. Meaning that even though the image failed to load, the Pokémon that you were trying to import over’s sprite palette would be corrupted.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Lather, rinse, and repeat for the backsprite. That won’t be covered here as I don’t have a backsprite for this young chap. The backsprite is located directly after the Pokémon it’s inserted for. Don’t worry about getting the palette correct on the backsprite, it will use the palette of the first image.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;ADDITIONAL STEPS FOR POKÉMON EMERALD:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;As Pokémon Emerald uses animations, additional steps must be taken in order to get the sprite to animate. Open unLZ-GBA and prepare to get cracking.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The animations are located around 500. Go to that number and then click next/previous until you arrive at the Pokémon you replaced earlier (for me, that’s Elekid.)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Looks like Elekid was located at 593. Okay, here comes the somewhat tricky part. Click “Save as...” and open the sprite in mspaint. Also open the sprite that you created before in another mspaint window. (Just launch MSPaint twice to get the second window.)&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Now you can see how the animations work. They’re simply two sprites stacked on top of each other. So, in order to replicate this, we simply do exactly that. Stack our custom sprite on top of itself.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Click on the window with the sprite that you created, and press ctrl+A to select all of it, and then ctrl+C to copy it. Then go back into the Animations sprite and paste (ctrl+V) into the window.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Cool! Now, repeat for the bottom half. Unfortunately this time you will have to manually place the sprite in place. If you wish for it to actually do something in its animation, you can edit the custom sprite as well.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Now save the animated ones and import them in unLZ-GBA! Use the following import settings:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;END OF EXCLUSIVE POKÉMON EMERALD SECTION.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;And you’re all done! The Pokémon that you created will now be available over the one you deployed it over! To move onto the next step in creating your custom Pokémon, which includes movesets, names, stats, evos, and etcetera, please wait until the next tutorial!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Tutorials/Entries/2010/9/16_Making_Custom_Pokemon_files/Screen%20shot%202010-09-16%20at%206.12.34%20PM.png" length="25826" type="image/png"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Visual Boy Advance</title>
      <link>http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Tutorials/Entries/2010/9/14_Using_Visual_Boy_Advance.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">94552c86-00cc-4e6b-8c75-b7f287bb9b38</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2010 15:36:03 -0400</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Tutorials/Entries/2010/9/14_Using_Visual_Boy_Advance_files/Screen%20shot%202010-09-14%20at%203.35.51%20PM.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Tutorials/Media/object008_1.png&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:221px; height:124px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Visual Boy Advance is one of the most essential utilities in your Hacking Tool belt. Well, not really, but without it there’d pretty much be nothing.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;So first thing’s first, open VBA in the VisualBoyAdvance folder in the Hacking Tools download of this site. Alternatively, you can get it &lt;a href=&quot;http://vba.ngemu.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Once it’s open, check out the minimalist interface:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Well, I mean like, what were you expecting? Obviously you’ll spend most of your time messing around with the File, Option, Cheats, etc. thingies. Now let’s get started loading a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.doperoms.com/&quot;&gt;ROM&lt;/a&gt;. Preferably one of your own, but hey, I won’t judge. Whatwhosaidthat? Anyway, click File, then Open. Alternatively, hold down ctrl and press O.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;After this, select where you have your ROM saved. It can be either in .BIN, .GBA format, or .ZIP format. Make sure it’s on a drive that you have write access to as well, for more reasons than just saving that will be covered later on.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Once the ROM is loaded, you are presented with an extremely welcome screen. It should look exactly how it looked/looks on your actual Game Boy.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Here are the default controls for Visual Boy Advance. They can be changed at any time by going to Options &gt; Joypad &gt; Configure &gt; 1...&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;There’s really nothing more to it. I personally just use the default control scheme because there’s nothing wrong with it. There are some other basic things that you should know about VBA before diving into actual ROM hacks. The first of these things you should know, are called Save States.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A Save State does exactly what it sounds like it does, which is saves your current state in the game. If you wanna get technical, it saves the RAM of the Game Boy to a file and allows you to resume at a later date, much like the Hibernation mode that of a modern day laptop. Anyway, using Save States is rather straightforward:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Clicking on Slot 3 in this example would write a new save state to slot 3. If I chose 1 or 2, I’d be overwriting the save states in them already. I would highly recommend using Save States over the built save feature, as not only is it more reliable, but it is also faster and more precise. To load a save state, you would obviously do just that:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Looks similar, right? Well let’s see what happens when we load it:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Just as expected, here we is where I made my save state earlier. Please keep in mind that every time you edit a ROM, simply reloading a save state isn’t enough to append the changes that you made. You must instead go to File &gt; Open each time.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Another cool VBA trick is the “Speed” feature. Since we’re playing on a much more powerful machine than an actual Game Boy, it makes sense that we should be able to play it at breakneck speeds, right? Try holding down the Space button (or whatever button you may have set it to) and see what happens.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;There’s not really a picture for this, but it’s pretty much self explanatory. Hold space, go fast. Release space, go regular speed.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Now, as for recording your fabulous hacks. Before we start recording however, I would suggest you set the text speed to FAST. It gets boring if you don’t!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Now, as for the actual recording, everything you need is under the Tools menu. Click on Tools &gt; Record... &gt; Start AVI Recording:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Almost as soon as you press Start, you wil be presented with a Save As dialog. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;In this simply type in the name as you would in any other Windows application and press Save. A new dialog box will appear. Set it to Uncompressed if it isn’t already set, and click OK.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;NOTE: Click OK, don’t press Enter. In most cases, pressing Enter will press the Start button in the game and the Menu will annoyingly pop up immediately while you’re recording.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Congratulations! You’re now recording! Here are some tips:&lt;br/&gt;	1)	Make sure the viewer will have enough time to read whatever text is on screen. I usually read it quickly in my head twice before pressing “Z”&lt;br/&gt;	2)	Ensure that your recording isn’t too long. It will waste RAM on your computer, and the audio might slowly desync if you record for more than like five minutes.&lt;br/&gt;	3)	When you mouse out of the window (if you do not have it set to continue playing) the recording will pause as well and pickup seamlessly where you left it off.&lt;br/&gt;	4)	DO NOT EVER USE THE SPEED UP FEATURE WHILE YOU ARE RECORDING. I can’t stress this enough. It’s the number one issue I have when I watch other hack vids. You’re recording Full Frames, so when you “speed up,” the game doesn’t. Your viewer is then forced to watch an extremely slow version of what you thought was “fast.”&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;To stop recording, simply reverse the process that we did a few steps ago:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Voila! You now have a cute little .AVI file that can go straight to youtube or into your favorite movie editor.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We’re almost done here, just one more thing to go over. Cheats. VBA supports “Action Replay” (Codebreaker) cheats, as well as GameShark Advanced ones. It also has a custom Code system that you might see around the web. To check out the cheats go to Cheats &gt; Cheat List...&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This is almost entirely self-explanatory by this point, but I’ll run you through it quickly so that you get an understanding. Sometimes you may need a cheat such as “Have all Gym Badges” in order to get Pokémon with HMs to obey you for demonstrative purposes. To do this, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/&quot;&gt;search around&lt;/a&gt;, for either Action Replay or Gameshark codes for your specific games.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Here’s an example for Action Replay and Pokémon Emerald to give the player all the different types of Poké Balls: 085938bb99ff313d2dafd7395d796510. Since it’s Action Replay, click “CodeBreaker...” in the screenshot above and fill in the information in the pop up window.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;As you can see, the Cheats are enabled. Click okay and check to see if they worked in the game.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Yep! It’s a success! Utilize cheats to manipulate small things that you may need for the purposes of demonstrating your actual hacks. Cheats will save/load along with Save States, so make sure to manage them accordingly.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;And that pretty much concludes this first tutorial! It went awfully in depth (A screen shot for practically every little step). The other tutorials won’t be as childish. But come on, you gotta get the basics down!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Things to Remember:&lt;br/&gt;	1)	ROMs must be reloaded if they are edited&lt;br/&gt;	2)	Save states are important and preferred to regular saving&lt;br/&gt;	3)	You can hold down “Space” to accelerate gameplay&lt;br/&gt;	4)	Do not speed up while recording&lt;br/&gt;	5)	Cheat lists save with save states&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;And that’s it! Feel free to shoot me an email at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:vgmoose@gmail.com/&quot;&gt;vgmoose@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; if you have any further questions!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Tutorials/Entries/2010/9/14_Using_Visual_Boy_Advance_files/Screen%20shot%202010-09-14%20at%203.35.51%20PM.png" length="54426" type="image/png"/>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
