<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss xmlns:iweb="http://www.apple.com/iweb" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog</title>
    <link>http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Blog</link>
    <description>Well, here is the sudden but inevitable blog:</description>
    <item>
      <title>All I do is haaaaxkkck</title>
      <link>http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Blog/Entries/2011/2/26_All_I_do_is_haaaaxkkck.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">a2442b13-6453-49eb-a79e-e45369215158</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 07:59:53 -0500</pubDate>
      <description>Pok&#xE9;mon Black and white are coming out soon and I did a hacxkkie amajig for them.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I also put up a preliminary fifth gen download link. I included a lot of tools from the fourth gen download that I was familiar with in addition to pptxt, for text editing. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Also, you all probably have not noticed, but I updated the fourth gen download so that it&#x2019;s actually useful. It has everything you need in addition to detailed help files. All it&#x2019;s really missing is a map editor, which doesn&#x2019;t actually exist at this time so I&#x2019;m feeling pretty good about that...&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Yeeeeeahhhh...</description>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Blog/Entries/2011/2/26_All_I_do_is_haaaaxkkck.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New video! And maybe Program?</title>
      <link>http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Blog/Entries/2011/2/19_New_video%21_And_maybe_Program.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">3cfe110c-7b63-44c8-a9aa-93a386f76a66</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2011 07:54:32 -0500</pubDate>
      <description>I told you guys that I wasn&#x2019;t dead! And it&#x2019;s all new content too! Kind of...&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I mean, it isn&#x2019;t the promised Creepypasta BUT THAT IS PROBABLY BEING WORKED ON.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Your Interactive Adventure can blaaaaaaaagh. Maybe I&#x2019;ll make a fourth generation IA LOLMFAO. No I won&#x2019;t.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Anyway, I intend on doing more fourth generation videos. Then maybe even fifth gen if the process is similar enough.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Also, I had a thought. A program similar to A-text that would edit the fourth generation text (or at the very least in heart gold and soul silver). VGText? Or simply V-text maybe? It&#x2019;s too bad I&#x2019;d have to make it for Windows... I&#x2019;m not very familiar with the process, although Visual Basic doesn&#x2019;t look that hard to pick up.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;We&#x2019;ll see bros!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;PS: I don&#x2019;t know if any of you saw, (you probably didn&#x2019;t), but I tried to make a Tumblr to see if my videos would catch on there with... no success. Oh well. This old standby is fine...</description>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Blog/Entries/2011/2/19_New_video%21_And_maybe_Program.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#x2019;m Not Dead!</title>
      <link>http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Blog/Entries/2010/10/10_Im_Not_Dead%21.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">3a96b557-cf2a-478a-84f2-281ab63e0e82</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2010 00:18:18 -0400</pubDate>
      <description>This is literally just an update to let you know that I&#x2019;m still alive! AND YES, THIS IS STILL GOING TO GET DONE EVEN IF IT KILLS ME. I have a chunk of time to work on it on Tuesday, so I think I shall do that then. With any luck, it&#x2019;ll be finished.&lt;br/&gt;&#x2028;Sorry this time. It&#x2019;s really just laziness now that I&#x2019;ve overcome that trainer-in-battle issue. I also installed Windows 7 as a virtual machine as opposed to Windows XP, and I&#x2019;d like to do another tutorial soon. Maybe even one detailing how to use the GTS to hack Pok&#xE9;mon in the current games.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;So yeah, that&#x2019;s all I&#x2019;ve got. Again, not that it matters, because nobody reads this. But whatever.</description>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Blog/Entries/2010/10/10_Im_Not_Dead%21.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DUDE PROGRESS UPDATE</title>
      <link>http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Blog/Entries/2010/9/19_DUDE_PROGRESS_UPDATE.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">c87556da-0505-4fd7-93ef-b0a869cae710</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2010 23:47:21 -0400</pubDate>
      <description>CAN YOU BELIEVE IT? I CAN NOT BELIEVE IT.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Okay, no, but seriously, I need to go to bed. Here&#x2019;s some shizz from the Interactive Adventure:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Like seriously, that was a lot of work. YOU DON&#x2019;T EVEN KNOW. At least it&#x2019;s finally out of the way. The rest of the Interactive Adventure should (hopefully) be downhill from here on!&lt;br/&gt;&#x2028;THAT&#x2019;S ALL I GOT!! MOOSE OUT.</description>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Blog/Entries/2010/9/19_DUDE_PROGRESS_UPDATE.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Working on Custom Pok&#xE9;mon Tutorial</title>
      <link>http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Blog/Entries/2010/9/18_Working_on_Custom_Pokemon_Tutorial.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">1de04984-fbcb-447e-8127-1c5d8e1e014a</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2010 01:01:58 -0400</pubDate>
      <description>As you may have, but probably didn&#x2019;t notice, there&#x2019;s a new tutorial entry under the tutorials page. It partially details how to insert your own custom Pok&#xE9;mon into the game. It&#x2019;s a work in progress, and is kind of a challenge to write, because I usually still even run into problems and have to discover my own workaround solutions to them. I guess that&#x2019;s just part of being a hacker though... maybe.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Not much else is going on. I got a huge RAM upgrade for my computer (2GB to 8GB) so vmware and the like run at super full speed, which is nice. I guess.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;TTYL LOL.</description>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Blog/Entries/2010/9/18_Working_on_Custom_Pokemon_Tutorial.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VBA Tutorial Up!</title>
      <link>http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Blog/Entries/2010/9/14_VBA_Tutorial_Up%21.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">b6173ce9-cf90-4b95-8f42-40ca5ce27a4e</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2010 17:21:26 -0400</pubDate>
      <description>That actually took about a billion more years than I thought that it would&#x2019;ve. I&#x2019;m not even kidding. Maybe it&#x2019;s just the ridiculous amount of detail I went into. I don&#x2019;t even think any one needs a VBA tutorial, so I honestly don&#x2019;t know what all that was about. I&#x2019;m thinking Advance Map, or Advance Text will be next, as they are excellent tools for beginners. Also, I&#x2019;m terrified of attempting to explain scripting, so I shall put that off as long as I have to.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;And yes, as usual the Interactive Adventure is being worked on. I&#x2019;m still trying to decide if I want it to keep going or if I just want to finish it. I mean, I think it&#x2019;d be cool if I could keep adding chapters to it and it would appear to go on forever, maybe even branch out in a choose-your-own-adventure style thing. Then again, that is so much infinitely more work, it isn&#x2019;t even funny. So yeah, I&#x2019;ll stick to ending it now, then if I feel completely motivated later I&#x2019;ll extend the story. I think it&#x2019;s a good ending though, ya&#x2019;ll should be happy(?).&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;EDIT: Added a scrollbar to allow all of the comments to show on the Comments page. Not like they&#x2019;re all just spam anyway, but whatever.</description>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Blog/Entries/2010/9/14_VBA_Tutorial_Up%21.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thinkings and Worklike Creatures</title>
      <link>http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Blog/Entries/2010/9/13_Thinkings_and_Worklike_Creatures.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">1a14fa92-96bd-45ea-8bcb-e4f7df3412d5</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2010 17:10:23 -0400</pubDate>
      <description>So like, I was thinking about what exactly I&#x2019;m going to do for the Tutorials. I&#x2019;m currently torn between just a video of me demonstrating it with my voice commenting, a list of every step with pictures, and even an interactive flash tutorial. The video would be the easiest and maybe even the most useful, however, it would kind of defeat the purpose of people even bothering to visit this site... Maybe I could just talk about it a bunch. I&#x2019;d also still probably include a shortcut key with pictures or reminders for the video that can be referenced quickly. The list of every step is an interesting one, and it&#x2019;d look nice too, however, there are some things that you really just need to see to understand. The interactive flash tutorial is obviously the most work, but it&#x2019;d be SO COOL OMG.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;So yeah, that&#x2019;s all I got. I&#x2019;ll probably either choose Video or Interactive Flash Tutorial. But you know how I am with all things Interactive... *whimper* I&#x2019;M WORKING ON IT STILL. I&#x2019;m thinking either this weekend... or next... uh, that sounds realistic right? I just hope it&#x2019;s worth it in the end. So many people have already liked the first pieces, so it&#x2019;d only make sense to finish &#x2018;er up.</description>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Blog/Entries/2010/9/13_Thinkings_and_Worklike_Creatures.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Which Deadspace is Awesome</title>
      <link>http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Blog/Entries/2010/9/12_Deadspace_is_Awesome%21.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">b3b6b7b3-4e60-47ce-ad7d-d461dc6a7998</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2010 14:49:34 -0400</pubDate>
      <description>Okay, well now that I have your attention, (or not), the Comments and Downloads sections are up! I&#x2019;m still working on slowly adding all of the Videos to the video page. It&#x2019;s not an easy, task; I may just forget doing full power descriptions as I&#x2019;ve been doing. Is that even how you use a semicolon? I don&#x2019;t think it is...&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Uh, oh yeah. In order to make this an actual &#x201C;blog&#x201D; entry or whatever I need to like talk about something generic. LIKE DEADSPACE OMG. Deadspace Extraction. I played with a friend last night through the co-op story mode (11 PM to 7 AM, if you&#x2019;re curious), and it did not let us down on the creep factor. I can&#x2019;t decide if the rail shooter aspect added or detracted from the experience, but it was pretty awesome. I WOULD RECOMMEND IT TO YOU. OR ELSE&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Yes, that is all. I might add more depth to the backpack page if it becomes necessary.</description>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Blog/Entries/2010/9/12_Deadspace_is_Awesome%21.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Website!</title>
      <link>http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Blog/Entries/2010/9/11_New_Website%21.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ca101dd4-7b82-48f0-b858-c7edf2b0a1e1</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2010 16:30:25 -0400</pubDate>
      <description>Well, this is pretty cool right? iWeb is actually good for something! With... any luck... at all there will be lots of things here, such as Pok&#xE9;mon Hack downloads, or maybe, in the distant and slash or not so distant future tutorials. First things first though&#x2013; Pok&#xE9;mon Interactive Adventure. It is happening. Honest. It will take a while, but I have already privately uploaded (as some of you have so keenly noticed) the next pieces of the adventure. Unfortunately, unlike the earlier break in work, these ends don&#x2019;t tie up nicely at one single endpoint. So for now, I will continue uploading privately until the next time they all meet together. (Which according to the &#x201C;script&#x201D; is also at the end...) SORRY IT&#x2019;LL BE DONE SOON THOUGH MAYBE.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;What else? That&#x2019;s really all I&#x2019;ve got for ya&#x2019;ll (assuming at least more than one person is reading this...) I&#x2019;m off to go play Deadspace: Extraction for the first time now, and I hope I don&#x2019;t cry.</description>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Blog/Entries/2010/9/11_New_Website%21.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <iweb:dateFormat>EEEE, MMMM d, yyyy</iweb:dateFormat>
    <iweb:baseURL>http://vgmoose.rickyayoub.com/VGMooses_Backpack/Blog</iweb:baseURL>
    <iweb:maximumSummaryItems>25</iweb:maximumSummaryItems>
  </channel>
</rss>
